To be alive
ที่จะมีชีวิตอยู่
is something really wonderful.
เป็นสิ่งที่วิเศษจริงๆ
What do I do from now on?
ฉันจะทำอย่างไรต่อจากนี้
A pothole. Aren't these formed when a meteorite hits the ground?
เป็นหลุมบ่อ สิ่งเหล่านี้ไม่ได้เกิดขึ้นเมื่ออุกกาบาตกระทบพื้นหรอกหรือ?
I'll be dead if I encounter such things again.
ฉันจะตายถ้าฉันเจอเรื่องแบบนี้อีก
I won't be as lucky
ฉันคงไม่โชคดีเท่าไหร่
all the time.
ตลอดเวลา.
I can only count on this skill.
ฉันสามารถพึ่งพาทักษะนี้ได้เท่านั้น
'HIDDEN" All I can do
'ซ่อน' ทั้งหมดที่ฉันทำได้
is to hide.
คือการซ่อน
EPISODE 4: MONKEY, WHA—?
ตอนที่ 4: ลิง WHA—?
♫Looking at the end of the entangled karma♫
♫มองที่จุดสิ้นสุดของกรรมที่พันกัน♫
♫Even my back is full of enemies♫
♫แม้แต่แผ่นหลังของฉันก็ยังเต็มไปด้วยศัตรู♫
♫Thousand of creatures♫
♫ สิ่งมีชีวิตนับพัน ♫
♫who are arrogant and ready to charge♫
♫ที่หยิ่งทะนงและพร้อมที่จะชาร์จ♫
♫Dive for alive♫
♫ดำน้ำเพื่อชีวิต♫
♫Climb for life♫
♫ไต่เขาเพื่อชีวิต♫
♫A chaotic state that no one can survive♫
♫สภาวะที่ไม่มีใครสามารถอยู่รอดได้♫
♫Take this as my stage♫
♫ใช้นี้เป็นเวทีของฉัน♫
♫Is this over?♫
♫ จบแล้วเหรอ ♫
♫But I'm not done♫
♫แต่ฉันยังไม่เสร็จ♫
♫Even if you didn't see the fatal silk♫
♫ถึงจะไม่เห็นไหมมรณะก็ตาม♫
♫you'll be eaten by me if you fall into the web♫
♫เธอจะถูกกินโดยฉันถ้าคุณตกลงไปในเว็บ♫
♫Deeper... inside♫
♫ลึก...ข้างใน♫
♫Spider pride made a cruel mark♫
♫ความภาคภูมิใจของแมงมุมสร้างรอยอันโหดร้าย♫
♫in this chest again♫
♫ในอกนี้อีกครั้ง♫
♫Finding the perfect way isn't enough♫
♫การหาทางที่สมบูรณ์แบบไม่เพียงพอ♫
♫The shredded life must be reformed♫
♫ชีวิตที่แหลกสลายต้องปฏิรูป♫
♫Think desperately♫
♫คิดอย่างสิ้นหวัง♫
♫Fight desperately♫
♫ต่อสู้อย่างสิ้นหวัง♫
♫The so-called reality. Feel a bit cold♫
♫สิ่งที่เรียกว่าความจริง รู้สึกหนาวเล็กน้อย ♫
♫Keep living the spider way♫
♫ ใช้ชีวิตตามวิถีแมงมุม ♫
♫Wait and see♫
♫รอดูกันต่อไป♫
SO I'M A SPIDER, SO WHAT?
ฉันเป็นแมงมุม แล้วไง
I had decided not to run away,
ฉันตัดสินใจที่จะไม่วิ่งหนี
but I still ran away.
แต่ฉันก็ยังวิ่งหนี
I hope this path leads to safety.
ฉันหวังว่าเส้นทางนี้จะนำไปสู่ความปลอดภัย
THE MANTIS-LIKE MONSTER THAT LIVES IN THE LOWER STRATUM
สัตว์ประหลาดเหมือนตั๊กแตนตำข้าวที่อาศัยอยู่ชั้นล่าง
OF GREAT ELROE LABYRINTH.
ของเขาวงกตเอลโรที่ยิ่งใหญ่
GOOD AT POWERFUL PHYSICAL ATTACKS WITH SICKLES.
เก่งในการโจมตีทางกายภาพที่ทรงพลังด้วยเคียว
The Lower Stratum of Great Elroe Labyrinth.
ชั้นล่างสุดของ Great Elroe Labyrinth
I'm only told now that this is the Great Elroe Labyrinth.
ตอนนี้ฉันเพิ่งบอกไปว่านี่คือเขาวงกต Great Elroe
It's even the Lower Stratum
แม้กระทั่งชั้นล่าง
and the habitat of powerful monsters.
และที่อยู่อาศัยของมอนสเตอร์ที่ทรงพลัง
I would rather not know this.
ฉันขอไม่รับรู้เรื่องนี้ดีกว่า
This mantis must be stronger than the snake.
ตั๊กแตนตำข้าวนี้ต้องแข็งแกร่งกว่างู
Could the snake actually be unimportant here?
งูอาจไม่สำคัญจริง ๆ ที่นี่?
No...
ไม่...
The mantis is just too strong.
ตั๊กแตนตำข้าวนั้นแข็งแกร่งเกินไป
GREATER TARATECT. LEVEL 18.
TARATECT ที่ยิ่งใหญ่กว่า ระดับ 18
THE EVOLVED SPIDER MONSTER.
มอนสเตอร์สไปเดอร์ที่วิวัฒนาการ
CARNIVOROUS. FATAL VENOMOUS FANGS.
กินเนื้อเป็นอาหาร เขี้ยวพิษร้ายแรง
Is that what I'll become when I evolve?
นั่นคือสิ่งที่ฉันจะเป็นเมื่อฉันวิวัฒนาการ?
How can I defeat this monster?
How can I defeat this monster?
I'll eat a monster that I can defeat.
I'll eat a monster that I can defeat.
Other than that, I'll just hide.
Other than that, I'll just hide.
My survival is depended on hiding now.
My survival is depended on hiding now.
I can't even have a good night sleep.
I can't even have a good night sleep.
This is horrible.
This is horrible.
I have to eat before this value is used up.
I have to eat before this value is used up.
But food is easy to get.
But food is easy to get.
I only realised while I kept going
I only realised while I kept going
that there are monsters of higher level in this lower stratum.
that there are monsters of higher level in this lower stratum.
The similarity of these monsters is...
The similarity of these monsters is...
SCHOOL OF ELROE
SCHOOL OF ELROE
Here I come.
Here I come.
That they're all venomous.
That they're all venomous.
LOWER STRATUM VENOMOUS TEAM
LOWER STRATUM VENOMOUS TEAM
Being venomous is awesome.
Being venomous is awesome.
Even if I'm found, they may just let me go.
Even if I'm found, they may just let me go.
ELROE EFEJICOTE. LEVEL 3.
ELROE EFEJICOTE. LEVEL 3.
ABILITY IDENTIFICATION FAILED.
ABILITY IDENTIFICATION FAILED.
These river snails are everywhere. Why aren't they eaten?
These river snails are everywhere. Why aren't they eaten?
I shall go ahead then.
I shall go ahead then.
I'll eat now.
I'll eat now.
ALTHOUGH IT WAS SHORT, THANKS FOR WATCHING. SO I'M A SPIDER, SO WHAT? THE END.
ALTHOUGH IT WAS SHORT, THANKS FOR WATCHING. SO I'M A SPIDER, SO WHAT? THE END.
I'm almost dead.
I'm almost dead.
What is this?
What is this?
Such creatures shouldn't exist!
สิ่งมีชีวิตดังกล่าวไม่ควรมีอยู่!
For example,
ตัวอย่างเช่น,
this is just like old kitchen waste that was cooked in warm milk
มันก็เหมือนกับขยะในครัวเก่าๆ ที่ปรุงด้วยนมอุ่นๆ
in a hot summer.
ในฤดูร้อน
Proficiency achieved a certain level.
ความสามารถบรรลุระดับหนึ่ง
ACID ENDURANCE UPGRADED FROM LEVEL TWO TO THREE. Acid endurance upgraded from level two to three.
ความทนทานต่อกรดอัพเกรดจากระดับสองเป็นสาม ความทนทานของกรดอัพเกรดจากระดับสองเป็นสาม
Hey! What kind of attribute is this?
เฮ้! นี่เป็นแอตทริบิวต์ประเภทใด?
I really don't want to eat such things anymore.
ฉันไม่อยากกินของแบบนี้อีกแล้ว
However...
อย่างไรก็ตาม...
However my principle is not to waste food.
อย่างไรก็ตาม หลักการของฉันคือไม่เสียอาหาร
Seriously...
อย่างจริงจัง...
I will eat it when there's no other choice.
ฉันจะกินมันเมื่อไม่มีทางเลือกอื่น
Because there's no sun,
เพราะไม่มีแดด
I don't even know how long I've been walking.
ฉันไม่รู้ด้วยซ้ำว่าฉันเดินมานานแค่ไหนแล้ว
I'm afraid I have been walking on this path for days now.
ฉันเกรงว่าฉันเดินอยู่บนเส้นทางนี้มาหลายวันแล้ว
I'm so anxious.
ฉันกังวลมาก
What if this road leads to the Bottom Stratum?
จะเกิดอะไรขึ้นถ้าถนนสายนี้นำไปสู่ชั้นล่าง?
Annoying. Stop imagining.
น่ารำคาญ หยุดจินตนาการ
It must be leading to Middle Stratum.
จะต้องนำไปสู่ชั้นกลาง
It should be, right?
มันควรจะใช่มั้ย?
I must find something edible this time.
คราวนี้ต้องหาของกินได้แล้ว
I just finished my sentence.
ฉันเพิ่งจบประโยคของฉัน
ELROE DINO MONSTER. LEVEL 7 AND 8. ABILITY IDENTIFICATION FAILED.
เอลโร ไดโน มอนสเตอร์ ระดับ 7 และ 8 การระบุความสามารถล้มเหลว
This is the Lower Stratum indeed. Their levels are so high.
นี่คือชั้นล่างแน่นอน ระดับของพวกเขาสูงมาก
The one with level 8 may evolve soon.
ผู้ที่มีระดับ 8 อาจมีวิวัฒนาการในไม่ช้า
But you will not be able to live til then.
แต่คุณจะไม่สามารถมีชีวิตอยู่ได้จนถึงตอนนั้น
Hooray!
ไชโย!
Condition fulfilled.
เป็นไปตามเงื่อนไข
The title "Venom Master" obtained.
ได้รับฉายา "พิษมาสเตอร์"
As a result of being a Venom Master,
จากการเป็น Venom Master
level one venom synthesis skill and level one venom magic skill obtained.
ได้รับทักษะการสังเคราะห์พิษระดับ 1 และทักษะเวทมนตร์พิษระดับ 1
-Is it venom? It's venom. -Proficiency achieved a certain level.
- พิษหรือเปล่า? มันเป็นพิษ - ความสามารถบรรลุระดับหนึ่ง
-So much venom. Today is a good day for venom. -Venomous fangs are upgraded to level eight.
- พิษมาก วันนี้เป็นวันดีสำหรับพิษ - เขี้ยวพิษได้รับการอัพเกรดเป็นระดับแปด
I'm so full...
อิ่มจังเลย...
Okay.
ตกลง.
"VENOM MAGIC. VENOM SYNTHESIS." Let's confirm these skills.
"เวทย์มนต์พิษ การสังเคราะห์พิษ" มายืนยันทักษะเหล่านี้กันเถอะ
Let's see.
มาดูกัน.
Venom magic.
เวทมนตร์พิษ
I still don't know how to use magic. So I'll just leave it aside for now.
ฉันยังไม่รู้วิธีใช้เวทย์มนตร์ ดังนั้นฉันจะทิ้งมันไว้ก่อน
Venom synthesis.
การสังเคราะห์พิษ
Should I try it?
ฉันควรลองไหม
Whisper.
กระซิบ.
Pray.
อธิษฐาน
Then,
จากนั้น
chant!
สวดมนต์!
Time for the show.
เวลาสำหรับการแสดง
Come on!
มาเลย!
Venom synthesis!
พิษสังเคราะห์!
There are many unhappy incidents in life.
มีเหตุการณ์ที่ไม่มีความสุขมากมายในชีวิต
Something appeared.
มีบางอย่างปรากฏขึ้น
MATERIAL FOR VENOM SYNTHESIS, WEAK VENOM. SPIDER VENOM LEVEL EIGHT.
วัสดุสำหรับการสังเคราะห์พิษ พิษที่อ่อนแอ SPIDER VENOM ระดับแปด
"VENOM THAT CAN BE SYNTHESISED" I shall try making it.
“พิษที่สังเคราะห์ได้” ผมจะลองทำดู
WEAK VENOM
พิษที่อ่อนแอ
It's good that this appeared,
ดีที่สิ่งนี้ปรากฏขึ้น
but how should I use this?
แต่ฉันควรใช้สิ่งนี้อย่างไร
Put it in a bottle?
ใส่ขวด?
"WEAK VENOM WATER" I don't have such things.
"น้ำพิษอ่อน" ของแบบนี้ไม่มี
Besides, my magic value decreased.
นอกจากนี้ ค่าเวทย์มนตร์ของฉันลดลง
It's a little hard to use.
ใช้งานยากนิดหน่อย
However, compared to the all-out magical tools,
อย่างไรก็ตาม เมื่อเทียบกับเครื่องมือเวทย์มนตร์ทั้งหมด
these are at least usable.
อย่างน้อยก็ใช้งานได้
Such a space that has nothing is really troublesome.
พื้นที่ดังกล่าวที่ไม่มีอะไรเป็นปัญหาจริงๆ
I shall use the basic maze strategy here,
ฉันจะใช้กลยุทธ์เขาวงกตพื้นฐานที่นี่
which is to walk along the wall on the right.
คือเดินไปตามกำแพงด้านขวา
But this place is really big.
แต่สถานที่นี้ใหญ่มาก
I'm in a burrow but I don't feel the sense of closure.
ฉันอยู่ในโพรงแต่ฉันไม่รู้สึกถึงการปิด
Although there are stones everywhere,
แม้ว่าจะมีหินอยู่ทุกที่
I still can see the vastness of nature.
ฉันยังคงเห็นความเวิ้งว้างของธรรมชาติ
Being in here
อยู่ในนี้
makes me feel how small my existence is.
ทำให้ฉันรู้สึกว่าการดำรงอยู่ของฉันมีขนาดเล็กเพียงใด
In my previous life,
ในชีวิตก่อนหน้านี้ของฉัน
even when I watched shows about the secret worlds
แม้แต่ตอนที่ฉันดูรายการเกี่ยวกับโลกลึกลับ
I didn't feel touched.
ฉันไม่ได้รู้สึกสัมผัส
Because the beautiful view in the picture
เพราะวิวสวยในรูป
is a faraway world to me.
เป็นโลกที่ห่างไกลสำหรับฉัน
But now that I'm here,
แต่ตอนนี้ที่ฉันอยู่ที่นี่
a world that I'm living in,
โลกที่ฉันอาศัยอยู่
it isn't irrelevant to me.
มันไม่เกี่ยวข้องกับฉัน
I can't be indifferent.
ฉันไม่สามารถเฉยได้
Something is closing.
มีบางอย่างกำลังปิด
BAGRAGRATCH. LEVEL 14. ABILITY IDENTIFICATION FAILED.
แบกรากรัทช์ ระดับ 14. การระบุความสามารถล้มเหลว
What kind of dangerous thing is that?
นั่นมันอันตรายประเภทไหนกันนะ?
Run before it finds me.
วิ่งก่อนที่มันจะพบฉัน
What's going on?
เกิดอะไรขึ้น?
BAGRAGRATCH. ABILITY IDENTIFICATION FAILED.
แบกรากรัทช์ การระบุความสามารถล้มเหลว
I have to run faster.
ฉันต้องวิ่งให้เร็วขึ้น
They look strong and they're in a group.
พวกเขาดูแข็งแกร่งและอยู่ในกลุ่ม
I have no chance of winning.
ฉันไม่มีโอกาสชนะ
Monkey? It looks a little different from those just now.
ลิง? มันดูแตกต่างจากตอนนี้เล็กน้อย
So fast.
เร็วมาก.
Seriously? Another style.
อย่างจริงจัง? อีกสไตล์.
No. If I were hit by the fist,
ไม่ ถ้าฉันโดนหมัด
I would be dead.
ฉันจะตาย
Continuous attack of fatal punch. I can't feel anything than fear.
การโจมตีต่อเนื่องของหมัดร้ายแรง ฉันไม่รู้สึกอะไรนอกจากความกลัว
I'm moving too obviously because of anxiousness.
ฉันเคลื่อนไหวอย่างเห็นได้ชัดเกินไปเพราะความวิตกกังวล
You can't do anything if I hold your fist.
คุณไม่สามารถทำอะไรได้ถ้าฉันกำหมัดของคุณ
How is that? Unhappy?
เป็นอย่างไรบ้าง? ไม่มีความสุข?
Oh no!
ไม่นะ!
I'm saved!
ฉันรอดแล้ว!
Although I feel like it brought it to itself,
แม้ว่าฉันจะรู้สึกว่ามันนำมันมาสู่ตัวเอง
I still won.
ฉันยังคงชนะ
Last strike!
นัดสุดท้าย!
Did I win?
ฉันชนะหรือไม่
Experience level achieved a certain target.
ระดับประสบการณ์บรรลุเป้าหมายบางอย่าง
Upgraded from level three to four.
อัพเกรดจากระดับสามเป็นสี่
Basic abilities are improved.
ความสามารถพื้นฐานได้รับการปรับปรุง
The scream before death shocked me,
เสียงกรี๊ดก่อนตายทำให้ฉันตกใจ
but my level is upgraded.
แต่ระดับของฉันได้รับการอัพเกรด
I'm going to taste it now.
เดี๋ยวจะไปชิมครับ
I'm full...
ฉันอิ่มแล้ว...
It is not bitter at all,
มันไม่ขมเลย
but it's still not tasty.
แต่ก็ยังไม่อร่อย
Pigs and cows from my previous life were so great.
หมูและวัวจากชาติก่อนของฉันยอดเยี่ยมมาก
I'm sleepy.
ฉันง่วง.
Because I haven't been sleeping well.
เพราะฉันนอนไม่ค่อยหลับ
Hence I'm so sleepy after food.
ดังนั้นฉันจึงง่วงนอนมากหลังอาหาร
If I can't find a way to sleep well,
หากฉันหาวิธีนอนหลับฝันดีไม่ได้
my body will not be able to take it.
ร่างกายของข้าพเจ้าจะรับไว้ไม่ได้
Bring me more meat.
เอาเนื้อมาเพิ่ม
What's going on? I'm feeling the chill.
เกิดอะไรขึ้น? ฉันรู้สึกหนาว
It hurts.
มันเจ็บ.
Seriously?
อย่างจริงจัง?
In order not to be found, I camouflaged.
เพื่อไม่ให้ถูกพบ ข้าพเจ้าจึงพรางตัว
Could the scream that monkey made before it died
เสียงกรีดร้องที่ลิงทำก่อนที่มันจะตายได้ไหม
release some special scent?
ปล่อยกลิ่นพิเศษ?
So they're back for revenge?
ดังนั้นพวกเขากลับมาเพื่อแก้แค้น?
There are so many of them. I can never defeat them.
มีมากมายของพวกเขา ฉันไม่สามารถเอาชนะพวกเขาได้
They still need some time to climb up.
พวกเขายังต้องการเวลาในการปีนขึ้นไป
Odd. The rock here is different.
คี่ หินที่นี่แตกต่างกัน
I can't climb up.
ฉันปีนขึ้นไปไม่ได้
No choice. I have to move side way.
ไม่มีทางเลือก. ฉันต้องเดินไปทางด้านข้าง
It hurts...
มันเจ็บ...
There's no way to run.
ไม่มีทางที่จะวิ่งได้
Although this is tough,
แม้ว่าสิ่งนี้จะยาก
this is my house after all.
นี่คือบ้านของฉัน
I have to keep going.
ฉันต้องไปต่อ
It hurts!
มันเจ็บ!
Horrible. This is tricky.
แย่มาก นี่เป็นเรื่องยุ่งยาก
And they are half way here now.
และพวกเขาก็มาถึงครึ่งทางแล้ว
It would be good if I can throw something.
มันคงจะดีถ้าฉันสามารถขว้างอะไรออกไปได้
Venom synthesis.
การสังเคราะห์พิษ
SPIDER VENOM. LEVEL EIGHT.
พิษแมงมุม ระดับแปด
Take this!
เอานี่!
Trying to attack from the side?
พยายามที่จะโจมตีจากด้านข้าง?
My magic value isn't quite enough.
ค่าเวทย์มนตร์ของฉันไม่เพียงพอ
I can't pour my venom there.
ฉันไม่สามารถเทพิษของฉันที่นั่น
Great. They've stopped moving.
ดีมาก พวกเขาหยุดเคลื่อนไหวแล้ว
This shall buy me some time.
นี้จะช่วยซื้อเวลาให้ฉัน
This is not the time to save strength.
นี่ไม่ใช่เวลาที่จะรักษาความแข็งแกร่ง
Once again!
อีกครั้ง!
These fellows are smart.
คนพวกนี้ฉลาด
If you're so smart, you should know there's no point defeating such a small spider.
หากคุณฉลาดมาก คุณควรรู้ว่าไม่มีประโยชน์ที่จะเอาชนะแมงมุมตัวเล็ก ๆ เช่นนี้
It looks like there are more of them now.
ดูเหมือนว่าจะมีมากขึ้นในขณะนี้
What should I do?
ฉันควรทำอย่างไรดี?
If this keeps going on, I'll die.
ถ้าเป็นแบบนี้ต่อไปฉันจะตาย
Take this.
เอาอันนี้
Great. Use them as the road blocks.
ดีมาก ใช้เป็นเครื่องกีดขวางถนน
It can buy me some time.
มันสามารถซื้อเวลาให้ฉันได้
How is this possible?
เป็นไปได้อย่างไร?
In order to not stop those at the back from attacking, they sacrificed themselves.
เพื่อที่จะไม่หยุดกองหลังจากการจู่โจม พวกเขาเสียสละตัวเอง
I can't hold anything back.
ฉันไม่สามารถถืออะไรกลับ
This is the final battle between me and them.
นี่คือการต่อสู้ครั้งสุดท้ายระหว่างฉันกับพวกเขา
Only when one party is dead, this will end.
เฉพาะเมื่อฝ่ายหนึ่งตาย สิ่งนี้จะจบลง
Have you forgotten how weak you are?
ลืมไปหรือยังว่าตัวเองอ่อนแอแค่ไหน?
Your opponent isn't someone unimportant.
คู่ต่อสู้ของคุณไม่ใช่คนไม่สำคัญ
They're expendables who are not afraid to die.
เป็นของใช้สิ้นเปลืองที่ไม่กลัวตาย
You can't defeat them just by joking around.
คุณไม่สามารถเอาชนะพวกเขาได้เพียงแค่ล้อเล่น
Alright!
เอาล่ะ!
Oh no!
ไม่นะ!
It hurts...
มันเจ็บ...
I can't take this anymore.
ฉันทนไม่ไหวแล้ว
"SMALL TARATECT UPGRADED FROM LEVEL FOUR TO FIVE" Experience level achieved a certain target.
"อัพเกรด TARATECT ขนาดเล็กจากระดับสี่ถึงห้า" ระดับประสบการณ์บรรลุเป้าหมายที่แน่นอน
Level upgraded to five.
ระดับอัพเกรดเป็นห้า
Great timing.
ช่วงเวลาที่ยอดเยี่ยม
Can I make it in time?
ฉันสามารถทำได้ทันเวลาหรือไม่
That was close.
มันปิด.
Although I've recovered,
แม้ว่าฉันจะหายดีแล้ว
losing my home is saddening.
การสูญเสียบ้านของฉันเป็นเรื่องที่น่าเศร้า
I still have other tricks.
ฉันยังมีเคล็ดลับอื่น ๆ
If even this doesn't work, I'm dead.
ถ้าแม้จะไม่ได้ผลฉันก็ตาย
But if I don't give it a go,
แต่ถ้าฉันไม่ลอง
I'll be dead as well.
ฉันก็จะตายเหมือนกัน
Come on...
เอาล่ะ...
Take this!
เอานี่!
"SMALL TARATECT UPGRADED FROM LEVEL SIX TO SEVEN" Experience level achieved a certain target.
"TARATECT ขนาดเล็กอัปเกรดจากระดับหกถึงเจ็ด" ระดับประสบการณ์บรรลุเป้าหมายที่แน่นอน
"BASIC ABILITIES UPGRADED" Level upgraded to seven.
"อัพเกรดความสามารถพื้นฐาน" ระดับอัปเกรดเป็นเจ็ด
REWARD OF UPGRADED SKILL PROFICIENCY HIDING SKILL UPGRADED FROM LEVEL FIVE TO SIX.
รางวัลของทักษะที่อัปเกรดแล้ว ความสามารถในการซ่อนทักษะที่อัปเกรดจากระดับห้าเป็นหก
"DODGING SKILL UPGRADED FROM ONE TO TWO." I thought I would be dead.
"ทักษะหลบหลีกได้รับการอัพเกรดจากหนึ่งเป็นสอง" ฉันคิดว่าฉันจะตาย
PAIN REDUCING SKILL UPGRADED FROM LEVEL FIVE TO SIX. AND SKILL POINT.
ทักษะการลดความเจ็บปวดได้รับการอัพเกรดจากระดับห้าเป็นหก และจุดทักษะ
After defeating so many monsters, I've increased by two levels.
หลังจากกำจัดมอนสเตอร์จำนวนมาก ฉันก็เพิ่มขึ้นสองระดับ
How many are they?
พวกมันมีกี่ตัว?
BAGRAGRATCH. FROM LEVEL THREE TO SIX. ABILITY IDENTIFICATION FAILED.
แบกรากรัทช์ จากระดับสามถึงหก การระบุความสามารถล้มเหลว
I should have noticed when I see the similar names.
ฉันควรจะสังเกตเห็นเมื่อฉันเห็นชื่อที่คล้ายกัน
These must be the evolved version of those monkeys.
พวกนี้จะต้องเป็นรุ่นพัฒนาของลิงพวกนั้น
I must set more spider webs.
ฉันต้องตั้งใยแมงมุมเพิ่ม
How can they move that so easily?
พวกเขาจะเคลื่อนไหวได้อย่างไร?
Hold on!
เดี๋ยวก่อน!
This can't be real.
นี้ไม่สามารถเป็นจริง
I would surely be dead if I were hit by it.
ฉันคงตายแน่ถ้าโดนมันโจมตี
And I have no place to stay.
และฉันไม่มีที่อยู่
If I have to keep looking down,
ถ้าฉันต้องก้มหน้าลงเรื่อยๆ
I may show my weakness.
ฉันอาจแสดงความอ่อนแอของฉัน
They will not miss such a good chance.
พวกเขาจะไม่พลาดโอกาสดีๆ เช่นนี้
There's no time to hesitate.
ไม่มีเวลาที่จะลังเล
First this,
อย่างแรกนี้
then...
แล้ว...
They're indeed creatures who learn well.
พวกมันเป็นสิ่งมีชีวิตที่เรียนรู้ได้ดี
They use their bodies to make paths for those at the back to attack.
พวกเขาใช้ร่างกายสร้างเส้นทางให้คนข้างหลังโจมตี
Most of the webs are useless now.
เว็บส่วนใหญ่ไม่มีประโยชน์ในขณะนี้
They sacrificed themselves to make way again.
พวกเขาเสียสละตัวเองเพื่อหาทางอีกครั้ง
But if they keep progressing with this method, their amount will decreased as well.
แต่ถ้าใช้วิธีนี้ไปเรื่อยๆ ปริมาณก็จะลดลงด้วย
If this keeps going on, they'll all be dead by the time they reach me.
หากสิ่งนี้ยังคงดำเนินต่อไป พวกเขาทั้งหมดจะตายเมื่อมาถึงฉัน
With the precondition
ด้วยเงื่อนไขเบื้องต้น
that these fellows don't start attacking.
ว่าเพื่อนเหล่านี้จะไม่เริ่มโจมตี
Oh no!
ไม่นะ!
Take this!
เอานี่!
SPIDER VENOM. LEVEL EIGHT.
พิษแมงมุม ระดับแปด
Experience level achieved a certain target.
ระดับประสบการณ์บรรลุเป้าหมายบางอย่าง
Level upgraded to eight.
ระดับอัพเกรดเป็นแปด
I'll deal with this one first.
ฉันจะจัดการกับเรื่องนี้ก่อน
The next one...
อันต่อไป...
The next one is so quick. It's on me now.
ตอนต่อไปเร็วมาก มันอยู่ที่ฉันแล้ว
But it's too naive.
แต่มันไร้เดียงสาเกินไป
Good. Where's the other one?
ดี. อีกคนอยู่ไหน?
I'm going to faint.
ฉันจะเป็นลม
If I faint, I'll surely be dead.
ถ้าฉันเป็นลม ฉันคงตายแน่
My sight is becoming blurry.
สายตาของฉันเริ่มพร่ามัว
But this is not the time to say this.
แต่นี่ไม่ใช่เวลามาพูดแบบนี้
Don't you run!
อย่าวิ่งสิ!
Three strikes of synthesised venom.
สามนัดของพิษสังเคราะห์
I can't do this anymore.
ฉันไม่สามารถทำเช่นนี้ได้อีกต่อไป
Experience level achieved a certain target.
ระดับประสบการณ์บรรลุเป้าหมายบางอย่าง
Level upgraded to nine.
ระดับอัพเกรดเป็นเก้า
That was really close.
นั่นอยู่ใกล้จริงๆ
Next, I only have to deal with all these fellows I caught.
ต่อไป ฉันต้องจัดการกับคนพวกนี้ที่ฉันจับได้เท่านั้น
Do you know? This is the prelude.
คุณรู้หรือไม่? นี่คือโหมโรง
The life of a spider.
ชีวิตของแมงมุม
I'm going to start singing.
ฉันจะเริ่มร้องเพลง
♫Ordinary♫
♫ธรรมดา♫
♫High school girl♫
♫ สาวมัธยม ♫
♫Ancient literature♫
♫วรรณกรรมโบราณ♫
♫Class♫
♫คลาส♫
♫Suddenly destroyed♫
♫ จู่ ๆ ก็ถูกทำลาย ♫
♫Time♫
♫เวลา♫
♫Process♫
♫กระบวนการ♫
♫Awareness♫
♫การรับรู้♫
♫Conscious♫
♫มีสติ♫
♫Became a spider♫
♫กลายเป็นแมงมุม♫
♫So confusing♫
♫ สับสนจัง ♫
♫Running here and there in chaos, little spider♫
♫วิ่งไปโน่นไปนี่ด้วยความโกลาหล เจ้าแมงมุมตัวน้อย♫
♫Being helpless in this big labyrinth♫
♫ อยู่ลำพังในเขาวงกตใหญ่นี้ ♫
♫Working hard to survive as the fittest, little spider♫
♫ทำงานหนักเพื่อเอาตัวรอดอย่างแมงมุมตัวน้อยที่แข็งแรงที่สุด♫
♫I'll just tell you. My power was weak at the beginning♫
♫ฉันจะบอกคุณ พลังของฉันอ่อนแอในตอนเริ่มต้น♫
♫Tricky enemies♫
♫ศัตรูเจ้าเล่ห์♫
♫Horrible food♫
♫อาหารที่น่ากลัว♫
♫Sweat and tears. What a misfortune♫
♫ทั้งหยาดเหงื่อและน้ำตา ช่างโชคร้ายเหลือเกิน♫
♫Don't give up even if your house is burnt down♫
♫อย่าท้อถอยแม้บ้านจะถูกไฟไหม้ ♫
♫But my heart wants my house back♫
♫แต่หัวใจอยากได้บ้านกลับคืนมา♫
♫A dream-like Isekai world of reincarnation♫
♫โลกแห่งการกลับชาติมาเกิดที่เหมือนฝันของอิเซไก♫
♫Needless to be said, the successful people♫
♫ไม่จำเป็นต้องพูดคนที่ประสบความสำเร็จ♫
♫are reincarnated as beautiful women♫
♫ได้กลับชาติมาเกิดเป็นสาวงาม♫
♫What? There's no skill that can turn things back?♫
♫อะไร? ไม่มีทักษะใดที่สามารถย้อนกลับได้ ♫
♫Identify. Spin silk. Toss. Shoot♫
♫ระบุ ปั่นไหม. โยน. ยิง♫
♫Focus. Be patient. Eat. Hide. Dodge♫
♫โฟกัส อดทน กิน. ซ่อน. ดอดจ์♫
♫Powerful silk. Venom synthesis. Drugs synthesis♫
♫ผ้าไหมทรงพลัง การสังเคราะห์พิษ การสังเคราะห์ยา♫
♫Gaido attack. Corrosive attack♫
♫ไกโดโจมตี การโจมตีที่กัดกร่อน♫
♫Various evil eyes. Final magic. Multiple avatars♫
♫ตาชั่วร้ายต่างๆ มายากลขั้นสุดท้าย อวตารหลายตัว♫
♫The final skill is to self destroy♫
♫ทักษะสุดท้ายคือการทำลายตัวเอง♫
♫Bring it on♫
♫มาเลย♫
♫I can do anything♫
♫ฉันทำได้ทุกอย่าง♫
♫Just go on if there's no other way♫
♫ไปเถอะถ้าไม่มีทางอื่น♫
♫Use all kind of skills♫
♫ใช้ทักษะทุกประเภท♫
♫I don't care even if I'm destroyed♫
♫ฉันไม่สนแม้ตัวฉันจะถูกทำลายก็ตาม♫
♫I don't want to die♫
♫ฉันยังไม่อยากตาย♫
♫I want to live♫
♫ฉันอยากมีชีวิตอยู่♫
♫I must keep living♫
♫ฉันต้องอยู่ต่อไป♫
♫Take this♫
♫ เอานี่ไป ♫
♫I don't want horrible game life♫
♫ฉันไม่ต้องการชีวิตในเกมที่น่ากลัว♫
♫Life should be better after reincarnation♫
♫ชีวิตควรจะดีขึ้นหลังจากการกลับชาติมาเกิด♫
♫Why is my beginning so miserable?♫
♫ทำไมการเริ่มต้นของฉันจึงน่าสังเวช ♫
♫I will not forgive you, admin D♫
♫ฉันจะไม่ให้อภัยคุณผู้ดูแลระบบD♫
♫The big labyrinth is just as dark today♫
♫เขาวงกตขนาดใหญ่ก็มืดมิดเหมือนวันนี้♫
♫Keep living or die trying♫
♫จงมีชีวิตอยู่หรือตายพยายามต่อไป♫
♫Although this kind of life is quite interesting♫
♫ถึงแม้ว่าชีวิตแบบนี้จะน่าสนใจทีเดียวก็ตาม♫
♫I still can't accept why♫
♫ฉันยังยอมรับไม่ได้ว่าทำไม♫
♫I am a spider♫
♫ฉันเป็นแมงมุม♫
You deserve this.
คุณสมควรได้รับสิ่งนี้
Although I reincarnated as a spider,
แม้ว่าฉันจะกลับชาติมาเกิดเป็นแมงมุม
I'm still alive.
ฉันยังมีชีวิตอยู่.
I survived!
ฉันรอดแล้ว!
Now that I think about it, I was hit by an earth dragon,
พอคิดดูแล้วโดนมังกรดิน
and when I escaped,
และเมื่อฉันหนีไป
my heart was filled with fear and regret.
หัวใจของฉันเต็มไปด้วยความกลัวและความเสียใจ
I broke the promise I made when my house was burnt down.
ฉันผิดสัญญาเมื่อบ้านของฉันถูกไฟไหม้
In order to survive, I kept running.
เพื่อความอยู่รอด ฉันจึงวิ่งต่อไป
Then I felt regret.
แล้วฉันก็รู้สึกเสียใจ
That's how I survived in these battles.
นั่นเป็นวิธีที่ฉันเอาชีวิตรอดในการต่อสู้เหล่านี้
I'm so happy.
ฉันมีความสุขมาก.
I'm so happy!
ฉันมีความสุขมาก!
Experience level achieved a certain target.
ระดับประสบการณ์บรรลุเป้าหมายบางอย่าง
Level upgraded to ten.
ระดับอัพเกรดเป็นสิบ
Conditions fulfilled.
เป็นไปตามเงื่อนไข
Small taratect may evolve.
taratect ขนาดเล็กอาจมีวิวัฒนาการ
EVOLUTION OPTIONS SPIDER MONSTER OR SMALL VENOMOUS SPIDER
ตัวเลือกวิวัฒนาการ ปีศาจแมงมุม หรือ แมงมุมพิษตัวเล็ก
I see. I'm already at level 10.
ฉันเห็น. ฉันอยู่ที่ระดับ 10 แล้ว
Because my level kept upgrading.
เพราะระดับของฉันยังคงอัพเกรด
Let's talk about evolution later.
มาพูดถึงวิวัฒนาการในภายหลัง
In this barren place
ในที่รกร้างแห่งนี้
I really can't evolve.
พัฒนาไม่ได้จริงๆ
By the way, the monkeys didn't call backup.
อีกอย่าง ลิงไม่ได้เรียกตัวสำรอง
This way goes uphill.
ทางนี้ขึ้นเนิน
Perhaps it's a way that leads to the Middle Stratum.
อาจเป็นวิธีที่นำไปสู่ชั้นกลาง
Hooray! Let's climb upwards!
ไชโย! ปีนขึ้นไปกันเถอะ!
So I can say goodbye to the most dangerous area.
ดังนั้นฉันสามารถบอกลาพื้นที่ที่อันตรายที่สุด
I wonder if it's because of my excitement, my body feels hot.
ฉันสงสัยว่าเป็นเพราะความตื่นเต้นของฉัน ร่างกายของฉันรู้สึกร้อน
I didn't know a spider's body temperature increases.
ฉันไม่รู้ว่าอุณหภูมิร่างกายของแมงมุมเพิ่มขึ้น
I can finally relax.
ในที่สุดฉันก็สามารถผ่อนคลายได้
What?
อะไร?
SO I'M A SPIDER, SO WHAT? NEXT EPISODE: CATFISH, DELICIOUS?
ฉันเป็นแมงมุม แล้วไง ตอนต่อไป: ปลาดุก อร่อย?
STAY TUNED.
คอยติดตาม.